<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EM WORSHIP</title>
    <link>http://www.emworship.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.emworship.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Leading worship with spirit and understanding</description>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 21:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 21:16:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>

    
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding your congregation</title>
      <link>http://www.emworship.com/blog/2014/10/05/understanding-your-congregation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.emworship.com/blog/2014/10/05/understanding-your-congregation</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jon Nicol wrote a post this week titled &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worshipteamcoach.com/blog/2014/09/02/10-ways-to-hate-your-congregation&quot;&gt;“10 ways to hate your congregation”&lt;/a&gt;. It’s worth a read, but I’d like to focus on a point he makes during the introduction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I was more focused on set lists and segues and building a band than I was forging relationships with those I was leading. I didn’t hate them, but I sure wasn’t loving them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of planning for a service involves understanding your congregation - what they’re going through, what big events have happened, what needs to be acknowledged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acknowledgement doesn’t have to be specific, either. It can be as simple as a general theme used to shape the songs and verses you choose. Specifics can be left to the notices, or intercessory prayer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the service is relevant to the needs of the congregation, it creates room for those people to feel understood and loved, and perhaps give them a nudge to reach out for support if needed. It enables a community of understanding, support, and compassion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, how do we find out what’s going on? In the lead up to your service, here are three things you can do.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lord, I Need You</title>
      <link>http://www.emworship.com/blog/2014/10/01/lord-i-need-you-by-matt-maher/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.emworship.com/blog/2014/10/01/lord-i-need-you-by-matt-maher</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Matt Maher’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lord, I Need You&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, from his 2013 album &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/nz/album/all-the-people-said-amen-live/id634140898&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;All The People Said Amen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, describes our relationship with and dependence on the Lord, particularly when we’re experiencing hardship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;talking-points&quot;&gt;Talking points&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much of the song focuses on the attributes of God - our defender, the one who guides us, who holds us together. Because of these attributes we can trust him with a relationship of dependence, one we know will endure any and all trials thrown at us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;hero-quote&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When I cannot stand I’ll fall on you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;peter-walking-on-water&quot;&gt;1. Peter walking on water&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bridge offers my favourite line, &lt;em&gt;“When I cannot stand I’ll fall on you”&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This reminds me of Peter, responding to Jesus’ call by walking on water in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Matthew%2014:22-33&amp;amp;version=NIV&quot;&gt;Matthew 14 22-33&lt;/a&gt;. When he “saw the wind” he started to sink. When the going got tough, fear and doubt crept in. Overwhelmed, he cannot stand. He cries out. &lt;em&gt;“Immediately Jesus reached out his hand and caught him”&lt;/em&gt;. In a sense he falls on Jesus, who raises him up. Christ is the sure foundation on the waters which threaten to swallow us.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome To EM WORSHIP</title>
      <link>http://www.emworship.com/blog/2014/10/01/1-welcome-to-em-worship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://www.emworship.com/blog/2014/10/01/1-welcome-to-em-worship</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to EM WORSHIP!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog focuses on &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;et mente&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, the mind, the understanding, of worship. Why do we worship in certain ways? How we can make sure the focus stays on God? How do we enable and encourage believers &amp;amp; non-believers, at any stage of their walk, to grasp the meaning of what they’re singing, praying, and participating in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;hero-quote&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Psallam spiritu et mente&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Psallam spiritu et mente”&lt;/em&gt;, is the motto of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://rscm.org.uk&quot;&gt;RSCM&lt;/a&gt;. It translates to &lt;em&gt;“I will sing with the spirit, and with the understanding also”&lt;/em&gt;, and is taken from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=1+Corinthians+14&quot;&gt;1 Corinthians 14:15&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So what shall I do? I will pray with my spirit, but I will also pray with my understanding; I will sing with my spirit, but I will also sing with my understanding. Otherwise when you are praising God in the Spirit, how can someone else, who is now put in the position of an inquirer, say “Amen” to your thanksgiving, since they do not know what you are saying? You are giving thanks well enough, but no one else is edified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t put it much better than that! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to get your insights in to worship too, because we certainly don’t have the answers! Join us on this journey.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    

  </channel> 
</rss>